# Meron Molla

## Junior Data Analyst | SQL Server

Graduate in Computer science and motivated in the data science field particularly data analytics, database administration, and Web development. Moderate experience with data wrangling, Modeling, visualizing and reporting using different techniques to optimize business performance. Passionate about education, technology & art.

meronalebachew44@gmail.com	$\times$
(919)-656-2736	•
NC, United States	0
meronmolla.com/	<u>::</u>
linkedin.com/in/meronmolla	in

github.com/MeronMolla 🔘

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Student

Self-employed

2020 - 2022

North Carolina, US

#### Tasks

- Building my own e-commerce online shopping website to sell products and generate supplementary income, and my living expense holds up by 30%.
- Experience with ETL, MS SQL Server (queries, stored procedures, data structures and analytics).
- Build covid-19 dashboards for African countries using Microsoft Power BI to increase community awareness about the disease by revealing cases and deaths.
- Extract product information from Amazon Website using Scrapy Python to show how product reviews and prices are correlated and also to enhance my skills. My data analytics experience intensified by 20% on the subject.

# **Sales and customer service**Perfume Paradise

2019 - 2020

Atlanta, Ga

#### Tasks

- Provided excellent customer service and achieved a high rate of client satisfaction and retention.
- Discussed promotions, products, and anything pertaining to better and more satisfactory service for the customer.
- Redirected calls as needed and worked with my supervisor to address any outstanding issues or concerns.
- Processing orders and transactions.
- Generating sales report

#### **EDUCATION**

MSc, Computer Science
American College of Technology

2020 - 2022

Graduate with High Honors

### **SKILLS**



#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

MS Degree In Computer Science (2020 - 2022)

#### **PORTFOLIO PROJECTS**

Click On The Link

- https://meronmolla.com/
- https://github.com/MeronMolla

#### LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

#### **INTERESTS**

Technology Business Art Education